-= CHD字幕組 原創翻譯 =-
字幕僅供翻譯學習交流 謝絕用於任何商業用途
翻譯：眷念
校對：dahongying
聖盃神器：骸骨之城
嗯，我知道
Yeah, no, I know,
可是我正要按你說的去做的
but when you tell me to do something, I'm gonna do it,
我馬上給他發郵件
so I'm e-mailing him right now.
嗯，我不知道他什麼時候回復
Well, I don't know how quick he's gonna get back
有時他並不查看郵箱，所以…
'cause you know sometimes he doesn't check, so...
好，詩朗誦會結束
Yeah, and after the poetry reading,
我不回家
I'm not going home.
我是說，今天我生日
I mean, it's my birthday,
我想去夜總會
so I want to go to a club.
不，西蒙，我不想對她撒謊
No, Simon, I'm not gonna lie to her.
我不告訴她就行了呀
I'm just not gonna tell her.
我來停車
Let me go park the truck.
- 等會見，好嗎？  - 好
- See you later, all right? - Okay.
喂，多蘿西，你好嗎？
Hi, Dorothea, how are you?
好吧，我很好，謝了
I'm good, thanks for asking.
我去打電話，多要張門票
So I'll just call, I guess, and get extra tickets.
好，就這樣
Yeah, sure.
- 我馬上做  - 你好
- I'll do it right now. - Hey, you.
是西蒙
Simon.
是的
Yeah.
你好，西蒙
Hi, Simon.
他說：「會打電話給我」
He says, "Call me."
是啊，是啊，我媽回來了
Yeah, yeah, she just got home.
她肯定聽得到，她就站在這兒
I'm sure she can hear you, she's standing right here.
- 你好，盧克  - 你好，克拉蕾
- Hey, Luke. - How's it going, Clary?
沒，我馬上換衣服
No, I'll get dressed quick.
要咖啡嗎？
Do you want some coffee?
你再講我就得遲到了
If we keep talking, I'm gonna be late.
就那兒見，拜拜
Yeah, I'll meet you there. Bye.
你是不是用了…
Did you just use the...
你覺得呢？
How are you feeling?
好吧，為什麼？
Fine, why?
記得晚上直接回來
You make sure you come straight home tonight.
拜託，媽媽 只是個詩歌朗誦會
Mom, come on. Just a poetry reading.
我懂的
I know.
拜拜
Bye.
喬絲琳，你需要跟她談談
You need to talk to her, Jocelyn.
不行，她還沒準備好
She's not ready, not yet.
不，她準備好了
Yes, she is.
沒好的是你
You're not.
另外，謝謝你能來
By the way, thanks for doing this.
他很在意詩朗誦會
His poetry means a lot to him.
誰叫我們是朋友
That's what friends are for.
「來…」
"Come
「難以抗拒的力量…」
"MY faux juggernaut
「我邪惡的下體…」
"My nefarious loins
「塗抹…」
"Slather
「用熾熱塗抹每一處隆起吧…」
"Every protuberance with arid zeal
「痛苦…」
"Agony
「折磨」
"Torment"
我聽不下去了，要再來杯咖啡嗎？
I can't listen to this. You want another coffee?
好
Yeah.
「包裹著的藏紅花瓣，低聲訴說死亡…」
"Like tiny crocus petals whisper death"
卡布奇諾和濃咖啡
Cappuccino and espresso.
「雨落大地」
"Rain drowns the earth"
「寒風穿過致病的壁毯」
"Shivering breezes weave through a morbid tapestry
「潰爛化膿」
"of festering disease
「我痛苦，全身腫脹」
"Turgid is my torment"
好了
There you go.
謝謝
Thank you.
「雨落大地…」
"Rain drowns the earth..."
剛才那金髮女孩蠻喜歡你啊
That blonde girl over there was totally flirting with you.
約她出來
Ask her out.
- 不，那不公平  - 為什麼？
- Nah, it wouldn't be fair. - Why?
嗯，因為…
Well, because...
為了某人，我得空著自己
Because I'm saving myself for someone else.
誰？
Who?
「是我的痛」
"Is my torment."
謝謝你，非常感謝
Thank you, thank you very much.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我覺得更不好
Think he's getting worse.
你是他好友，得跟他講
As his friend, you should probably tell him.
也許他詩歌很棒
Maybe his poetry is great,
我們不懂欣賞吧
we just don't know it yet.
進去看看
Let's go in here.
我想問下這符號的意思
I want to ask what that symbol means.
克拉蕾，我們不該進去
Clary, we'll never get in.
你個擔心鬼
Such the eternal optimist.
這可不像你
This is so not like you.
就去這一次啦
Just go with it for once.
這符號代表什麼？
What does that symbol mean?
- 什麼符號？  - 嗯，哪埵陴顫飽H
- What symbol? - Yeah, what symbol?
就在那兒 你沒… 你沒看見嗎？
It's right there. You don't... You don't see it?
沒
No.
酷斃了
Hey, that was cool.
嘿，我們進來了
Yeah, we're fitting in.
跟著跳 跟著跳
Move it, go with it.
克拉蕾，要來一杯嗎？
Clary, you want a drink?
好
Yeah.
克拉蕾，克拉蕾，那是什麼
Clary, Clary, what is it?
你沒看到嗎？
You didn't see that?
我真的看到
I know what I saw.
讓我們進去的那個男孩被殺了
They killed the guy that let us in the club.
- 你是喝迷幻藥了？  - 天啦，我沒喝，西蒙
- Did you drink something? - Yeah... No, Simon.
你知道，以前我就聽說過
You know, I've heard sometimes
有人把迷幻藥注射到他們鼻子
they pump hallucinogenic stuff into the air vents
這樣玩會很刺激
to make sure people have a good time.
好了，那你怎會沒事？
Okay, then how come you're fine?
我倆呼吸的是不同的空氣？
Did we breathe different air?
我不懂，回家好了
I don't know. Let's just go home.
- 你沒事吧？  - 沒事
- You okay?   - Yeah, fine.
你整整睡了一天
You've been sleeping all day.
而且你昨晚很遲回來
And you didn't come home till late last night.
是的，不過我有回來，對吧？
Yeah, well, I'm home, okay?
不准走
Well, you can't go.
我賣了另一幅畫
Well, I sold another painting.
一塊去慶祝一下
I wanted to celebrate with you.
慶祝你唯一的買家？
To what, your one buyer?
好吧，他是誰？
Who is this guy anyway?
他買你畫估計是愛上你了
He probably just buys your stuff 'cause he's into you.
你肯定像哄盧克那樣哄他的吧
I'm sure you'll just string him along like you do with Luke.
你幹嘛非得那樣說？
You really want to have that conversation?
那什麼意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
- 西蒙  - 他就像我哥
- Simon. - He's like my brother.
我可不認為他這麼想
I doubt he feels that way.
好吧，不過我要走了
Okay, well, I'm gonna go.
- 不，不，別走  - 別犯傻了
- No, no, you can't. - This is ridiculous.
- 你去哪堙H  - 我只是去加瓦-瓊斯咖啡廳
- Where are you going? - I'm just going to Java Jones.
- 我的天！  - 不，是我
- Jesus!     - No, just me.
走吧，西蒙
Come on, Simon.
克拉蕾 我有些事想告訴你，好嗎？
Clary. There's something I want to tell you, okay?
以後再說啦
We can talk about this later.
拜拜，弗蕾夫人
Bye, Mrs. Fray.
看，我突然畫了很多這些東西
Look, suddenly I'm drawing hundreds of these things,
我不懂怎麼搞的
and I have no idea what they are.
我不知道… 我想我快瘋了
I don't know. I think I'm going out of my mind.
也許你是《第三類接觸中》的那個主角
You know, maybe you're like the guy in Close Encounters.
大家認為他是妄想狂
Everybody thought he was paranoid,
但結果居然是…
and then there turned out to be, well...
幽浮，挺合理的，就像…
UFO, reasonable, like...
哎，天了，這怎麼可能發生
Oh, God, this isn't happening.
- 怎麼了？  - 這不可能
- What? - This isn't happening.
嘿，現在我被你嚇到了
Okay, now you're freaking me out.
克拉蕾，你是…
Clary, are you...
你在看什麼？
What are you looking at?
在這等我
Wait here.
喬絲，聖盃在哪？
Where's the Cup, Jocie?
你怎麼找到我？
How did you find me?
這得謝你女兒
You can thank your daughter for that.
為何我能看見你而別人不行？
Why can I see you and no one else can?
我還想問你呢？
I was going to ask you the same question.
我怎麼會跟你說話
I don't even know why I'm talking to you.
一個殺人狂，一個冷血殺手
You're a killer, a cold-blooded killer.
有這麼溫和的殺手？
As opposed to a peace-loving killer?
我很明白所看到的
I know what I saw.
你以為你明白
You think you know.
為什麼我會畫這些？
Why am I drawing this?
我猜對了，你不是凡人
So I was right, you're not a mundane.
等等，凡人？
Excuse me? What's a mundane?
就是人類
Someone from the human world.
我要不是人類，那我是什麼？
If I'm not a human, then what am I?
去找聖盃
Go find the Cup.
- 什麼時候發生的？  - 不，不
- When did this start? - No, no.
為什麼我會畫這些？
Why am I drawing this?
回答我！
Answer me!
西蒙
Simon.
你或許得接下，可能是你男友
Maybe you should answer that. Could be your boyfriend.
- 他不是我男友  - 那他知道嗎？
- He's not my boyfriend. - Does he know that?
拜託，這很吵
Please. It's annoying.
媽，我要回來了
Mom, I'm coming home.
不，不，不 你不能回家
No, no, no. You can't come home.
聽到了嗎？別回來
You understand me? You don't come home.
告訴盧克
You call Luke.
說瓦倫丁復活了，他會找到我
Tell him Valentine's alive and that he found me.
我愛你
I love you.
- 媽！ - 不，不！
- Mom!    - No, no!
媽！
Mom!
告訴瓦倫丁他不可能拿到聖盃
You tell Valentine he'll never have the Cup.
別喝… 別喝…
Don't you... Don't drink...
過來！別… 什麼？
Come here! Don't... What?
快點！
Come on.
對不起 對不起 你還好嗎？
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. You okay?
沒事，別動，好嗎？
All right, look, don't move, all right?
媽？
Mom?
來，起來
Come on. Come on.
夠了！夠了！夠了！
That's enough! That's enough. That's enough.
它死了
It's dead.
那該死的到底是什麼？
What the hell was that?
我說了你肯定不信
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
說說看
Try me.
它是邪靈
It was a demon.
你說得對
You're right.
我不信你
I don't believe you.
而那個東西
And that thing,
你在夜總會看到我殺死的那個…
that you saw me kill at the club, that...
也是一隻邪靈
That was also a demon.
邪靈會附身任何活物
Demons can take possession of any living creature.
你誰都不能信
You can't trust anyone.
即使那人你很熟悉
Even people you think you know.
那我幹嘛要信你？
So, why should I trust you?
因為我剛才救過你
I did just save your life.
多蘿西，快開開門
Dorothea, open up, please.
你能…
Can you...
你知道我媽發生了什麼嗎？
Do you know what happened to my mom?
你知道嗎？
Do you?
等等，你可以看到他？
Wait, you can see this guy?
當然可以 她是女巫
Of course she can. She's a witch.
從姜餅套房降級到了單臥室？
Downgraded from a gingerbread house to a one-bedroom?
你知道我媽在哪媔隉H
Do you know where my mom is?
對不起，我不清楚
Sorry. I have no idea.
嗯，她曾提到一個名字… 瓦倫丁
Well, she mentioned a name... Valentine.
- 你最好離開  - 不，請不要這樣
- You better leave. - No, please.
你不告訴我，我就不走
Not until you tell me something, anything.
看看骨牌占卜到什麼
Let's see what the cards have to say.
對不起，我不信這些…
I'm sorry, but you know that I don't believe in any of...
坐下
Sit.
把手在牌上過一遍
Run your hands over the cards.
我媽媽畫過這些
My mom painted these.
是的，你媽媽送的
Yes. They were a gift.
看看你拿到哪一張牌
Let's see which card gets picked.
大金盃
The Ace of Cups.
- 那是聖盃  - 那？
- That's the Mortal Cup. - So?
別理他
Ignore him.
這是聖盃神器
It's a Mortal Instrument,
我們族人三大聖物之一
one of the three holy objects of my people.
它怎麼在這兒？
What's it doing here?
我不明白這跟我媽有什麼關聯
I don't understand what any of this has to do with my mom.
你母親是暗影獵人，跟他一樣
Your mother was a Shadowhunter, like him.
不，我媽是個畫家
No, my mom is a painter.
她從沒跟你說過，對吧？
She never told you any of this, did she?
我只知道的是她消失了
All I know is that she's gone,
然後我不知道去哪塈鉿o
and I have no idea where to start looking for her.
讓我給你讀心
Let me read you.
有東西封印了你的回憶
There's something blocking your mind.
我猜是你媽媽僱請了高人來保護你
My guess is your mother hired someone very skilled to protect you.
- 保護什麼？  - 你的回憶
- From what? - Your own memories.
為什麼？
Why?
我不懂她要我忘記什麼
I don't remember anything she'd want me to forget.
等等
Wait.
很高興見到你
Nice to meet you.
搞什麼？
What the hell?
你嚇到我了
You scared me.
這究竟發生過什麼？
What the hell happened here?
- 我媽媽不見了  - 什麼？
- My mom's missing. - What?
有人抓了她，還毀了這
Someone took her and destroyed the place.
他正幫我找她
This guy is helping me find her,
你看不到他，而且他…
but you can't see him, and he...
克拉蕾
Clary.
好吧
Great.
好吧，現在我也看不到他了
Okay, now I can't see him, either.
傑斯·維蘭德，邪靈獵手
Jace Wayland, demon hunter.
西蒙·盧易斯，解鎖師
Simon Lewis, Keymaster.
你是門衛嗎？
Are you the Gatekeeper?
我不懂你在說什麼
I have no idea what you're talking about.
等等 什麼，你現在可以看到他了？
Wait. What, so you can see him now?
- 什麼？我當然能看到他  - 可我以為…
- What? Of course I can see him. - But I thought...
- 不…  - 你說什麼呢？
- No... - What are you talking about?
我被搞糊塗了
This is so confusing.
這是誰？
Who's this?
我爸爸，我兩歲時他就死了
That's my dad. He died when I was two.
克拉蕾，等等
Clary, a moment.
等等，你媽消失了
So, wait, your mom is gone,
你卻跟這染金髮的追星小伙在一起？
and you're hanging around with some dyed-blond wannabe Goth weirdo?
你在哪兒遇到他的？
Where'd you come across this guy?
- 不，我沒有 是他找我的  - 什麼？他找你
- No, I didn't. He found me. - What? He found you?
- 不，我知道這聽起來…  - 看看這個
- No, I know it sounds... - You should check this.
鄭重聲明，我頭髮金色是天生的
And for the record, my hair is naturally blond.
克拉蕾，克拉蕾，克拉蕾… 西蒙？
Clary, Clary, Clary... Simon?
她打過電話？
She called you?
你為什麼不接？
Why didn't you pick up?
要是知道這麼嚴重，我早接了
If I'd known it was serious, I would have picked up.
你都沒接怎麼會知道？
Well, how would you know if you didn't pick it up?
那是什麼？
What's that?
沒好事
Nothing good.
你懂她哪兒弄來這個的嗎？
Do you have any idea where she got this?
我得找盧克
I've got to find Luke.
太奇怪了，他車在這兒
It's so weird. His truck's here.
來吧 這邊
Come on. This way.
不，你在這等
No, you wait here.
幹嘛要聽你的？
Who made you the boss?
沒關係，這樣有人來能通知我們
It's okay. Just let us know if anyone comes.
我認識盧克好多年
I've known Luke all these years,
但我都沒下來過
but I've never been down here.
什麼？
What?
快點，夥計！
Come on, mate!
夥計，聽好…
Now, listen...
你要做的就是說真話
All you got to do, mate, is tell me the truth.
我說了，不知道聖盃在哪兒
I'm telling you, I don't know where the Cup is.
我知道你和喬絲關繫好
I know you and Jocie are close.
我可不是傻子？
I'm not stupid, am I?
別這樣回答
Don't answer that.
聽我說，夥計
Listen to me, mate.
只要告訴我聖盃在哪兒
Just tell me where the Mortal Cup is.
喬絲就會沒事
And then Jocie will be fine.
盧克，說啊，告訴我
Lukey, tell me. Tell me the truth.
我不知道
I don't know.
你可別惹我生氣
You don't want to make me angry.
- 我說了…  - 是嗎？
- I'm telling you... - Do you?
我再問一遍，夥計
I'm going to ask you again, mate,
聖盃在哪兒？
where's the Cup, huh?
我不知道
I don't know.
我們都需要它，盧克，不是嗎？
We all want the same thing, Lukey boy, don't we?
不同之處，我覺得你知道它在哪兒
Difference is, I think you know where it is.
不是嗎？
Don't you?
快點 快點 說啊！
Come on. Come on. Talk!
- 我們得走了  - 不，求你了，你要幫他
- We need to go. - No, please, you have to help him.
你不懂
You don't understand.
他們是瓦倫丁的人
They work for Valentine.
他是個死人 我幫不了他
He's a dead man. I can't help him.
他是我家人
He's like family.
奇了怪
You know what's really amazing
你看上去還挺像人類
is how much you actually look like a human.
很棒啊？
Isn't it great?
求你了
Please.
你要發狂了？你要變身了？
Are you gonna get mad? You're going to change?
我要看你變身
I want to see you change.
給我露露你怎麼變身的？
Show me how you can change. Huh?
看看 看看
Look at that. Look at that.
狼人來了
Dog boy's coming on.
你想搞我腿？
You want to hump my leg?
你搞我腿？喜歡這樣？
You hump legs? You like that?
要嗅我屁股嗎？
You want to smell my derriere?
我要看你　變身
I want to see you change!
告訴我喬絲琳把聖盃藏哪兒
You just got to tell me where Jocelyn hid the Cup.
然後你可以平安帶回她
Then you can have her back.
她會平安無事的
She'll be safe and sound.
我沒要她回來
I don't want her back.
我一點不在乎
I couldn't care less.
我這麼多年
I have spent years
一直在討好她和她的倔女兒，就是為聖盃
cozying up to that woman and her brat for the Mortal Cup.
潘伯恩，聽我說
Pangborn, listen to me.
我也想把聖盃給瓦倫丁
I want to be the one to give her to Valentine.
呀，對
Yeah, right.
你在犯大錯
You are making a big mistake.
我不信，你信他嗎？
I don't believe you. Do you believe him?
- 克拉蕾，快跑！  - 克拉蕾，聽我說！
- Clary, run!          - Clary, listen!
勞駕 警官？
Excuse me. Officer?
我要報案，有人闖入
I'd like to report a break-in.
一人失蹤
And a missing person.
有人闖入我朋友的家…
My friend's house got broken into, and...
- 她媽媽失蹤了  - 哦，不
- Her mom's missing. - Oh, no.
快跑！
Run!
- 你殺了兩個警察！  - 他們不是警察
- You killed two cops! - They weren't cops.
快走！
Let's go!
克拉蕾
Clary.
你不能留在這兒 他們會抓到你的
You can't stay here. They'll find you.
盧克怎麼會說他不在乎？
How could Luke say that he didn't care?
我從記事起就認識他了
I've known him for as long as I can remember.
他曾每晚都為我讀故事
He used to read to me every night.
他天天來校接我好幾年了
He's been picking me up at school for years.
也許這記憶不真實
Look, maybe those memories aren't real.
你不記得我說的了嗎？
Do you remember what I told you?
誰都不能相信
You can't trust anyone.
不，我要找回媽媽，我要回家
No, I need to find my mom. I have to go home.
- 我肯定漏了什麼！  - 聽我說，好嗎？
- There must be something that I missed! - Listen to me, okay?
我們會弄清的，但不是此時此地
We'll figure this out, but not here and not now.
你得到一個安全的地方
We need to get you to a safe place.
我是暗影獵人，克拉蕾
I'm a Shadowhunter, Clary,
我會誓死保護你
and I will protect you with my life.
你們在這兒，我以為你們緊跟著
There you guys are. I thought you were right behind me.
我丟了你們
I thought I'd lost you.
好吧，我跟著你
Okay. I'll follow you.
你確定嗎？他剛殺了兩個警察
Are you sure about that? 'Cause he just killed two cops.
呀，他們不是警察
Yeah, they weren't cops.
我覺得他們就是
They looked like real cops to me.
- 他們不是真警察  - 好吧
- They weren't real cops. - Okay.
那他們那兒弄來的警車？
So, where did they get the car?
他們不是真警察
They weren't real cops.
在這我們會很安全
We'll be safe in here.
這鬼地方是哪堙H
What is this dump?
這不是鬼地方
This isn't a dump.
只不過你看不見
You just can't see it.
到底怎麼了？他們做了什麼？
What the hell is going on? What are they doing in here?
- 這是被邪靈咬傷  - 克拉蕾
- It's a demon bite. - Clary.
傑斯，做點什麼！
Jace, do something!
接下來是不是你該撕掉你的襯衣
Is this the part when you start tearing off pieces of your shirt
包紮我的傷口呢？
to bind my wounds?
如果你要我把這身衣服脫下來
If you wanted me to take my clothes off,
只要你發話就行
you should've just asked.
只是有點發燒
It's just a fever.
她醒了
She's waking up.
我昏倒後你們給紋的？
I passed out, and you guys tattooed me?
我以為這只在賭城才會發生
Thought that only happened in Vegas.
- 這不是紋身  - 是圖符
- It's not a tattoo. - It's a rune.
它讓你擁有一切：
They have them for everything,
隱身術，強健之軀和自愈術
they make you invisible, strong, they heal.
它讓你可見
They also make you visible.
所以我突然可以看到他
That's why I could suddenly see him.
- 即使你不吃飯…  - 不
- Even if you're hungry... - No.
事實上，這圖符是讓你可以看到我們
The fact that the rune had an effect on you explains why you can see us.
我沒弄懂
I don't get it.
凡人是挺不過來的
Mundanes can't survive the process.
他們無法承受這圖符的力量，所以…
The runes are too strong for them, so...
現在，我們很確定你有暗影獵人的血脈
Now we definitely know you have Shadowhunter blood.
等等，那之前就不確定了？
Wait, it wasn't definite before?
她沒死，才讓我們更確定，是這樣的
Well, it became definite when she didn't die. Yes.
看看合不合身
Here, see if these fit.
我們這不是天天有貴客的
It's not every day we get guests in here.
尤其少見女客人
Especially not girls.
是啊
Yeah.
我們要叫警察來嗎？
Shouldn't we call the cops?
我指的是真警察
I mean, the real ones.
好主意
That's a great idea.
我只是不懂我們為何沒想到過
I just don't know why we haven't thought of that
在過去的這幾千年中
for the past thousand years.
霍奇在等她
Hodge is ready for her.
他想在藏書館單獨見她
He wants to see her alone in the library.
霍奇是誰？
Who's Hodge?
他是這堛瑰Y
He's in charge of the Institute.
好吧，我們走
Okay, let's go.
無數的暗影獵人曾來此尋求庇護
Hundreds of Shadowhunters used to seek asylum here.
但你也看到了
But, as you can see,
現在只剩我們這幾個了
right now, we're the only ones.
沒有聖盃，我們只能等死
Without the Mortal Cup, we're a dying breed.
要麼你是暗影獵人的後代
Either you're born of a Shadowhunter,
要麼你有喝過聖盃之水
or you have to drink from the Mortal Cup.
你來自
You coming?
遙遠的布魯克林，對吧？
Pretty far from Brooklyn, isn't it?
離傑斯遠點
Stay away from Jace.
你可能覺得霍奇有點古怪
You may find Hodge a little eccentric,
但他曾是最出色的暗影獵人之一
but he's one of the greatest Shadowhunters that's ever lived.
這給我
Here, give me that.
你不覺得這有點冒險
Don't you think it's a bit risky
讓一個完全陌生的人
inviting a complete stranger
闖進神院中心？
into the heart of the Institute?
不，我們可以相信她
No. I think we can trust her.
那她的凡人朋友呢？
And what about her mundane friend?
嗯，這是一時疏忽
Well, that was impulsive.
你一時疏忽，會弄砸事
When you're impulsive, things go badly.
當心
Just be careful,
自愈心碎的圖符是最疼的
the rune to fix a broken heart is the most painful one.
我保證適時讓他們離開
They'll be out of here in a day, I promise.
傑斯
Jace.
她曾是最出色的獵人之一
She was one of the best,
你的母親
your mum.
但我不明白為什麼她…
But I don't understand why...
昨天你還只是個普通的女孩
Yesterday you were just a normal girl.
今天彷彿感覺到
Today you feel as though
你的世界徹底翻天覆地改變了
your whole world has been turned upside down.
你必須知道一件事
There's only one thing you need to know.
那是你小時候聽到的故事
The stories you were told as a little girl
怪獸和夢魘
about monsters, nightmares,
篝火旁低訴的傳說…
legends whispered around campfires...
他們都是真的
They're all true.
- 邪靈？  - 對
- Demon?    - Yes.
邪靈？
Demon?
不，狼人不是邪靈
No. Werewolves aren't demons.
我們和地下生物有過停戰協議
We have a truce with Downworlders.
地下生物？
Downworlders?
是什麼？14號街以下的人？
What is that, like people below 14th Street?
嗯，「地下生物」包括很多
Well, "Downworlders" pretty much sums everything up,
吸血鬼，狼人和術士
vampires, werewolves, Warlocks.
術士，很酷啊
Warlocks. Cool.
你怎麼殺死一隻殭屍的？
So, how do you kill a zombie?
我們沒殺
We don't.
當然他們已經死了
Of course, they're already dead.
不，他們不存在
No. They don't exist.
那麼這就是大家所說的聖盃吧
So, that's the famous Cup everyone's talking about.
只是個模型，不過也對
A replica. But yes.
那你知道傑斯敏感易怒咯
You know, Jace has got a real chip on his shoulder.
你也一樣的
You would, too,
如果你小時候親眼看到你父親被殺
if you saw your father murdered when you were a child.
要不是他，我們全死了
If it weren't for him, we'd be dead.
我都說不清他救了我們多少次了
He saved our lives more times than I care to admit.
好吧
Right.
據傳說
The legend goes,
十字軍曾召喚過一位天使
the Crusaders summoned an angel,
天使拉齊爾
the Angel Raziel.
拉齊爾將自己的鮮血倒入聖盃
Raziel poured his blood into a cup,
那些喝過其血的人
and those who drank from it
變成半天使，半凡人
became half angel, half human.
暗影獵人
Shadowhunters.
這會遺傳給他們的子子孫孫
As did their children and their children's children.
有強大力量的族群
Beings of immense power,
足以恢復和平
strong enough to restore balance
保護世界，抵禦邪靈
and protect the world in a war against evil.
這是無贏家的鬥爭
A war that can never be won,
但永無休止
but must always be fought.
因為邪靈永生不息
Demons don't die easily.
但我們卻終有一死
Whereas we, we remained all too mortal.
你們幹嘛不用聖盃
Why didn't they just use the Cup
繁衍出更多的暗影獵人？
to create more Shadowhunters?
瓦倫丁也這麼說過
Valentine's exact words.
克拉夫－聖盃守護者
The Clave, the keepers of the Cup,
他們害怕其力量
they were afraid of using its power.
他們知道沒人能承受住聖盃的力量而存活
They knew that hardly anyone who drank from it survived.
瓦倫丁·摩根斯坦召集了一群朋友
Valentine Morgenstern drew a circle of friends together,
一群年輕妄想的暗影獵人
young, idealistic Shadowhunters,
幫他從克拉夫手堸膘鴗F聖盃
to help him steal the Mortal Cup from the Clave.
但瓦倫丁並不想保護人類
But he didn't want to protect humanity.
他相信暗影獵人可以進化
He believed there had to be an evolution of Shadowhunters,
變得更具力量
something more powerful.
他開始試著使用聖盃
He began experimenting, using the Mortal Cup.
並學會了召喚邪靈
He learned how to summon demons.
他甚至給自己注射過邪靈的鮮血
He even injected himself with demon blood
以此來控制他們
so he could control them.
他想統治一切
He wanted to rule.
為了阻止他，你媽媽
Your mother, to prevent that,
偷走了聖盃
stole the Cup from him,
而後消失不見
and vanished into thin air.
但要是只有她知道聖盃在哪堙A那麼…
But if she's the only one that knows where the Cup is, then...
也許不只她
Maybe she isn't.
她可能告訴某人了
Maybe she told someone else.
一個沒有人猜到她知道的人
Someone who doesn't know she knows.
賽任兄弟們在等她
The Silent Brothers are ready for her.
為什麼霍奇不一塊來？
Why didn't Hodge come with us?
他好多年沒離開神院了
He hasn't left the Institute in years.
有人說是詛咒
Some say it's a spell.
他有恐曠癥吧
He's agoraphobic.
是他嗎？
Is that him?
不，那是哈羅德，掃地工
No, that's Harold, the groundskeeper.
是他
That's him.
你想好要經歷這些了嗎？
Are you sure you want to go through with this?
我們會幫你解開回憶
We will help you to remember.
你會吵醒亡靈的
You'll wake the dead.
難以置信，這地方就在城市外
I can't believe this place is just outside the city.
歡迎來到　骸骨之城
Welcome to the City of Bones.
這是賽任兄弟汲取力量的源泉
This is where the Silent Brothers draw their power,
暗影獵人的骸骨和骨灰
from the bones and ashes of Shadowhunters.
他們都埋在這堙H
All of them are buried here?
對，有一天
Yes. One day,
我會在這
that's gonna be me.
我只能跟到這兒了
This is as far as I go.
你不會有事的
You'll be fine.
你之前試過嗎？
So you've done this before?
沒
No.
你必須傾聽自己的內心
You must listen with your mind.
媽？
Mom?
去，去
Go. Go.
克拉蕾，這是盧克
Clary, this is Luke,
我最好的朋友
my dearest friend.
你可以信任他
You can trust him.
你好，克拉蕾
Hi, Clary.
別說
Don't tell.
別碰那老東西
Don't touch that old thing.
只是個舊杯子，克拉蕾
It's just an old cup, Clary.
克拉蕾！克拉蕾，你還好嗎？
Clary! Clary, are you okay?
克拉蕾？
Clary?
封印比預想的要強
Your block is stronger than I anticipated.
解鈴還須繫鈴人了
It can only be undone by the one who put it there.
我不清楚繫鈴人是誰
I have no idea who put it there.
你寫出來了
You wrote it.
你記得是相反的印象
Your mind remembers the inverted image.
要換個角度看
Just have to look at it differently.
「貝恩」
"B-A-N-E."
- 貝恩  - 是誰？
- Bane.    - Who?
馬格努斯·貝恩，我記得他是個術士
Magnus Bane. He's a warlock. I should have known.
好，那找他去
Well, let's go talk to him then.
不能這樣去
Not like that.
你需要伊莎貝爾的協助
We're gonna need some help from Isabelle.
這是上衣
This is a top.
是連衣裙
It's a dress.
我穿不了
I can't pull this off.
就差雙合適的鞋子…
Well, actually, with the right shoes...
不，我是說…
No, I mean...
這衣服太緊，像包了一層皮一樣
This dress is so tight, it's like a second skin.
你難道沒有別的了嗎？
Don't you have anything else?
要是你穿得像凡人那樣去的話
If you go out looking like your mundane self,
我們接近不了馬格努斯·貝恩
we won't get within a hundred feet of Magnus Bane.
他是布魯克林的高級術士
He's the High Warlock of Brooklyn.
別抱怨了，過來
Now, stop complaining, come over here.
拿著
Hold this.
亞力克好像很討厭我
That guy Alec doesn't like me very much.
亞力克是我的兄弟
That guy Alec is my brother.
傑斯知道亞力克對他的感覺嗎？
Does Jace know how Alec feels about him?
很明顯嗎？
Is it that obvious?
這真沒什麼大不了的
It's really not that big of a deal.
對我也一樣
It isn't to me either.
但對克拉夫不同
But it is to the Clave.
規則不是我定的
I don't make the rules.
看，現在多漂亮
See? You look pretty.
幹嘛要穿得這麼妖艷
How is being dressed like a hooker
會幫我找到媽媽？
gonna help me find my mom?
放鬆點，那些只是我的衣服而已
Easy now, those are my clothes.
亞力克，她看上去漂亮吧？
Doesn't she look great, Alec?
她看上去就像
She looks like someone
留電話號碼在浴室牆上的人
whose phone number should be on a bathroom wall.
我覺得你很漂亮
I think you look great.
等等，我來過這
Wait, I've been here.
- 等等  - 怎麼了？
- Wait.     - What?
這樣更好點？
Is that better?
更好了
It's better.
嘿，嘿，嘿
Well, well, well.
瞧瞧這兒
Look-a here.
什麼風把人神的孩子們吹到這兒
I don't remember inviting any children of the Nephilim.
馬格努斯·貝恩，我們要談談
Magnus Bane. We need to talk.
我不喜歡你們
You know I don't like you guys.
但我還讓你們待在這兒
But I'll let you stay,
只是因為這火辣寶貝
but only because of the hot one.
- 謝謝  - 謝謝
- Thanks. - Thank you.
什麼？
What?
我說的是他
I meant him.
藍眼睛的那位
The one with the blue eyes.
還有克拉蕾
And because of Clary.
等等，你怎麼知道她名字？
Wait. How do you know her name?
跟我來
Come with me.
- 你媽媽呢？  - 她失蹤了
- Where's your mother? - She's missing.
原來如此
That explains it.
她每年都帶你來這兒
Every year, she brought you here.
從來沒有漏過一次
She never missed an appointment.
我在你身上下的咒語是最成功的
Not every spell turns out as perfect as the one I did on you.
一旦你開始畫天使圖符
As soon as you started drawing the angelic rune,
說明你的記憶又回來了
it was a sign your memory was surfacing.
我將此咒深藏在你記憶中
I had built that into your mind
她就能適時帶你回來封印
so that she knew when to bring you back.
暗影世界堛漱@切，你都會忘記
What you saw from the shadow world,
即使你看過
you would forget, even as you saw it.
可你越長大
But as you grew older,
你需要封印的次數也越來越多
you needed my treatment more frequently.
她知道有一天非得告訴你
She knew she had to tell you one day,
但想等你準備好後
but until you were ready,
她想封印回憶
she wanted to keep the block on your mind.
這就是她想做的
It was exactly how she wanted it.
我們要在這兒待多久？
How long do you think we're gonna be here?
西蒙，放鬆點，好嗎？
Relax, Simon, okay?
別喝！
Don't drink that!
西蒙！西蒙！
Simon! Simon!
時間會消磨封印
It'll wear off over time.
現在已經磨去了，要麼你不會來這兒
It's already wearing off, or you wouldn't be here.
我還是記不起來
I need to remember.
我媽沒有多少時間了
My mom doesn't have time.
求你了，你肯定能做點什麼
Please, there must be something you can do.
你就是買我母親畫的人
You're the one who's been buying all my mom's paintings.
你為什麼每幅都買？
Why did you buy all of them?
我清楚她需要錢
I knew she needed the money.
你甚至有我爸爸的畫像
You even have a portrait of my dad.
那不是你爸
That's not your dad.
他只是戰死在伊朗的一名士兵
He's a soldier who died in Iraq.
喬絲琳從沒見過他
Jocelyn never even met the guy.
有人請她畫的
She was asked to paint his portrait,
但這對一位寡婦來說太痛苦了
but it was too painful for the widow.
她保留著畫，所以…
She kept the picture so...
她就能假裝他是我爸爸
She could pretend he was my dad.
她做的一切都是為了你
Everything she did, she did for you.
你媽媽生命中的一切：
Your mother's whole existence,
逃跑，躲藏，謊言
the running, the hiding, the lies,
都是為了你的安全
were to keep you safe.
她有跟我說過什麼真話嗎？
Was anything she ever told me true?
你頭腦娷繭菑@幅寶藏圖，克拉蕾
There's a treasure map inside your head, Clary.
找到聖盃，它能帶你找到你媽媽
Find the Cup, and it will lead you to your mother.
他們把西蒙帶走了
They've taken Simon.
- 誰？  - 吸血鬼
- Who?   - Vampires.
別忘了
Just remember,
你媽媽躲避的正是暗影獵人
it was Shadowhunters your mother was running from.
我們去找西蒙
Let's go find Simon.
我們不能闖進吸血鬼的老巢，我們從沒試過
We can't break into a vampire's lair, we never learned.
- 又開始了你  - 傑斯，這你知道的
- Don't start again. - Jace, you know the rules.
夥計，我們來這幹嘛？
Guys, what are we doing here?
我們不是要找西蒙嗎？
I thought we were trying to find Simon.
我們知道他在哪，只是需要先拿些東西
We know where he is. We just need to pick up a few things.
這是什麼？你們和教堂有某種約定？
What is this, some kind of deal you have with the church?
邪靈在世界各地都有
Demons exist all across the world
而且外形各異
in their varying, different forms.
暗影獵人從不單信某個宗教
Shadowhunters cling to no particular religion,
因此，所有宗教都能協助我們作戰
and in turn all religions assist us in our battle.
我們自如穿梭在猶太教堂
We could have as easily gone to a Jewish synagogue
或神道教塔…
or a Shinto temple or...
在這
Here it is.
在每個教堂的祭壇底下…
Beneath every altar in every church...
都能找到這個
you'll find this.
那你們信仰什麼？
So, what do you believe in?
我信仰自己
I believe in myself.
我知道殺死邪靈是我的職責
I know my job is to kill demons.
其它我一概不信
I don't have to believe in anything else.
那天使拉齊爾呢？
What about the Angel Raziel?
那是美麗的傳說
Yeah, makes for a nice story.
- 但霍奇說…  - 是啊，霍奇
- But Hodge thinks... - Yeah, Hodge.
他還有很多沒說
He needs to get out more.
- 我原以為…  - 聽著，我一直在獵殺邪靈
- I thought... - Listen, I've been hunting demons
已經花掉了我三分之一的生命
for over a third of my life,
到目前為止，從未見過天使
and in all that time, I've never seen an angel.
這兒
Here.
這，你拿這個
Here, you take this one.
我不會…
I don't...
這，我教你
Here, let me show you.
這是一把殺吸血鬼的槍，必須瞄準他們的心臟
It's a vampire gun. Must pierce the heart.
推上來，對著胸膛
Push it up against the chest.
開火
Fire.
再裝槍 重發
Recharge. Then you're good to go again.
死人客棧？
Hotel of Death?
他們也有幽默感
You can't say they don't have a sense of humor.
快點
Come on.
- 她怎麼辦？  - 她很勇敢
- What is it about her? - She's brave.
我們暗影獵人都勇敢
We're Shadowhunters, we're all brave.
她不像我們那樣撫養長大，她不同
She wasn't raised like us, she's different.
她會連累我們被殺
She's gonna get us all killed.
是西蒙的襯衫
Simon's shirt.
他在上面
He's up here.
西蒙
Simon.
- 我的天，我的天，西蒙  - 克拉蕾
- Oh, my God, oh, my God, Simon. - Clary.
不，我能觸到他了！
No, I can feel him!
搭把手 快點，快點
Give me a hand. Come on, come on.
這該死的靴子！
These damn boots!
這兒
Here.
好
Here you go.
- 快點  - 夥計，穩住
- Come on. - Guys, steady.
慢點
Slowly.
他還活著！
He's alive!
小心
Careful.
快走，他們要的不是我
Go on. Get out. They don't want me.
要的是你，他們要的是聖盃
They want you, they want the Cup.
- 快點，走  - 天啊
- Come on. Let's go. - Oh, God.
快！
Let's go!
不，這兒
No, here.
- 這兒！  - 走！
- In here! - Go!
傑斯
Jace.
你身後！
Behind you!
快點！快點！
Come on! Come on!
克拉蕾！
Clary!
他們人數太多
There's too many of them.
抱點信念
Have a little faith.
跑！
Run!
傑斯，給我把短刀
Jace, I need a knife.
- 日出  - 快走
- The sun. - Let's go.
幫西蒙
You help Simon.
克拉蕾！
Clary!
抓住！
Hold on!
克拉蕾！
Clary!
謝謝
Thank you.
你救了西蒙
For saving Simon.
- 還好嗎？  - 我沒事，我沒事
- Are you okay? - I'm okay, I'm okay.
克拉蕾
Clary.
能和你談談嗎？
Can I talk to you?
行，我正要去看西蒙
Yeah, I was just gonna go see Simon.
- 我希望你離開這兒  - 什麼？
- I want you to leave here. - What?
你差點讓我們送死
You almost got us killed.
對不起，我們別無選擇
I'm sorry, we didn't have a choice.
要救西蒙，而傑斯…
I mean, we had to save Simon, and Jace...
傑斯應該拯救世界
Jace thinks he needs to save the world.
但你沒鼓勵他這麼做
But you don't need to encourage him to do it.
這就是你們要做的
But that's what you guys do.
對，我們　要做的
Yes, us. What we do.
我們是團隊，你是累贅
We're a team, you're deadweight.
- 凡人  - 我不是凡人
- A mundane. - I'm not a mundane.
你要是表現得有半點勇敢
And if you were half as brave as you pretend to be,
就得承認…
you'd admit that...
什麼？
What?
你承認你愛上了傑斯
You'd admit that you're in love with Jace,
這才是千真萬確的
and that's what this is really about.
你敢再這樣說一下…
If you ever say anything like that again...
我定殺死你
I'll kill you.
- 我暈了多久？  - 一整天
- How long was I out? - All day.
你的眼鏡
Found your glasses.
- 有一邊鏡片裂了  - 嗯
- One of the lenses cracked. - Yeah.
好神奇
How weird.
我似乎不需要它了
I don't seem to need them anymore.
那你在畫什麼？
So, what are you drawing?
沒什麼
Nothing.
- 你還好嗎？  - 還好
- You okay?     - Yeah.
這太瘋狂了
It was crazy.
對不起之前我不相信你
I'm sorry I didn't believe you before.
現在我信了
Now I get it.
還有…
And...
當時我昏倒了
And I must have passed out,
接著你就出現
and then you showed up.
聽著
Listen,
我知道我總是那個要被依賴的人
I know I've always been the one who needed you
比起你依賴我來
more than you needed me.
- 不是真的  - 是真的
- That's not true. - Yes, it is,
但我不在乎
but I never cared.
我只有媽媽，盧克和你了
I've only ever had my mom, Luke and you.
別亂想你對我來說不重要
Don't ever imagine that you weren't important to me.
- 好吧  - 好吧
- Okay.   - Okay.
你跟鋼琴有仇嗎？
What did that piano ever do to you?
好像失去唯一真愛一樣
You play it like you've lost your only love.
不幸的是我唯一真愛就是自己
Unfortunately, my one true love remains myself.
至少你不用愁遭拒絕
Well, at least you don't have to worry about rejection.
那也不一定
Not necessarily.
我有時會自我分裂，尋求刺激
I turn myself down occasionally just to keep it interesting.
你彈得很有熱情
You do play that with a lot of passion.
這才有問題
Well, that's the problem.
我不該投入太多感情
I play it with too much emotion.
本應該只是簡單地音符重現
It's supposed to be played with a simple representation of notes,
而不是詮釋
no interpretation.
音樂就該有感情
Music is supposed to have emotion.
邪靈對交錯的音調才有反應
Demons react to certain frequencies when two tones cross.
才能使他們癲狂
Drives them crazy.
看，巴赫發現這點並構建了一個體系
See, Bach discovered this and put it into a system using
用數字序列融合音調
a mathematical progression of tonal combinations
可以顯現邪靈
that allows us to expose demons.
那巴赫也是個暗影獵人咯？
So Bach was a Shadowhunter?
- 是的  - 這麼說…
- Yes.        - So...
巴赫對於邪靈們就像大蒜對於吸血鬼
Bach is to demons what garlic is to vampires.
也對吧
Kind of.
我是說：大蒜會被用盡
I mean, you can run out of garlic.
但音樂卻無止境
You can't really run out of music.
那堜騊菃A的玩意嗎？
Is that where you keep all your toys?
有趣得多
It's way more fun.
來吧
Come on.
這是穿梭門
It's a portal.
像百慕大一樣的自然現象
Like the Bermuda Triangle, it's a natural phenomenon.
神院圍繞它而建
The Institute was built around it.
據說神院是紐約最早的建築
Some say that the Institute was the first building in New York.
所以它…
So it's...
空間不都只是直線型的
Dimensions aren't all just straight lines.
也會有彎曲
There's bends,
折疊，凹角
folds and nooks.
有點難以解釋，不過
It's a little bit difficult to explain, but
穿梭門能帶你到任何你想去的地方
the Portal can take you wherever you want to go in this dimension.
一旦穿過表面
So, as soon as you break that surface,
你就會被送到你心底最深處
you're transported to wherever your deepest thoughts lie.
那意味著…
So that means...
- 我媽媽…  - 等下
- My mom... - Wait.
我們訓練一生才懂得使用它
We spend our entire lives training how to use it,
進入前要先想像一下所去之處
visualizing where it will take us before we step into it,
那必須要非常集中精力
and that takes incredible focus.
如果沒有經過正確訓練而進入的話
If you were to step into it without the proper training,
你將永無安定
you could end up in limbo,
永生困在記憶之中
lost in your own mind forever.
這兒
Here.
我做給你看
Let me show you.
快點
Come on.
別偷看
No peeking.
很酷吧，對吧？
Pretty cool, isn't it?
現在…
Now...
你和我…
You and I...
要慶祝你的生日
Have a birthday to celebrate.
你怎麼知道？
How did you know?
我之前找你，就查到過
Research. When I was trying to find you.
不會有人來這兒
No one comes up here anymore.
這媊搣顜畯
We have the place to ourselves.
美得窒息了
This is breathtaking.
抱歉，沒有蛋糕
Sorry there's no cake.
我原本就沒期望
Well, I was expecting nothing,
這已很棒了
so this is great.
不過，每個人都該在生日那天得到些什麼
Well, everyone should get something for their birthday.
你生日得到什麼？
What did you get?
大多數是武器
Weapons mostly.
希望沒讓你吃驚
I'm sure that doesn't surprise you.
現在沒有什麼會讓我吃驚
At this point, nothing really does.
當我九歲時…
When I was nine...
我父親送了我一隻隼
My father gave me a falcon.
他要我讓它聽話
He told me to make it obedient.
我本該弄瞎那隻鳥
I was supposed to keep the bird blind,
但我做不到
but I couldn't bring myself to do it.
相反的是，我撫摸它的翅膀
Instead, I touched and stroked its wings
直到它信任我
until it trusted me.
我以為完美地馴服了它
I tamed it to perfection.
我把它帶給父親
I took it to my father,
希望父親為我所做的感到驕傲
expecting him to be proud of what I'd done.
他說：
He said,
「我是要你讓他聽話」
"I told you to make it obedient.
「不是要你教它愛你」
"Instead, you taught it to love you.
「你沒有馴服它，你毀了它」
"You didn't tame it, you broke it."
他帶走鳥，並割了它的脖子
Then he took the bird and he broke its neck.
我當時哭了整整一夜，此後再沒哭過
I cried all night and I never cried again.
你原諒他嗎？
Did you ever forgive him?
他這麼做是要我強大
He did it to make me stronger.
那是你名字維蘭德的意義嗎？
Does that stand for Wayland?
午夜
Midnight.
瞧瞧這些
Watch this.
一個女孩說要一顆大寶石
When a girl says she wants a big rock,
但她並非就是這個意思
she doesn't literally mean a big rock.
每個暗影獵人都有屬於自己的魔石
Every Shadowhunter should have their own witchlight.
有人在
We have company.
那只是霍奇的鳥
That's Hodge's bird.
我們得走了
We should probably go.
是啊
Yeah.
我們真得走了
We should definitely go.
抱歉忘記告訴你會定時噴水
Sorry about the sprinkler system.
別提它了
I forgot about that.
要去睡了嗎？
You going to sleep?
累了嗎？
Well, aren't you tired?
我從沒這樣清醒
I've never been more awake.
- 西蒙，我以為你…  - 睡了？
- Simon, I thought you were... - Asleep?
之前是的
Yeah, I was.
我們只不過…
We were just...
下次，最好是
Next time, it might be a nice idea
你得說你已經有個男人在床上
to mention that you already have a man in your bed,
我們才不會這麼尷尬了
so we can avoid such uncomfortable situations.
你讓他到你床上？
You invited him to bed?
我知道這挺荒唐的，是不是？
I know, it's ridiculous, isn't it?
不可能一切合心意
We would never have all fit.
我沒有讓他到我床上
I didn't invite him into bed.
只是接吻而已
We were just kissing.
你太快丟掉我倆的愛了
How swiftly you dismiss our love.
傑斯…
Jace...
西蒙，很晚了，對不起吵醒你
Simon, it's late, and I'm sorry we woke you.
我也是
So am I.
去吧，去找他，去向他道歉
Go ahead. Go after him, go apologize to him,
去跟他說他才是特別的
go tell him just how special he really is.
- 別這樣！  - 哪樣了？
- Stop acting like that! - Like what?
好像你沒受傷一樣
Like nothing ever hurts you.
嗯，也許你應該想清楚的
Well, maybe you should have thought about that
在你親我之前
before you kissed me.
是我親你？
I kissed you?
別擔心，這對我也沒什麼了不起
Don't worry, it wasn't that special for me either.
西蒙，真的很抱歉，我還以為你在…
I'm really sorry, Simon, but weren't you just in the...
我只是在找你
I was just looking for you.
- 你要去哪兒？  - 回家
- Where are you going? - Home.
顯然我在這太久，不受歡迎了
It's clear I overstayed my welcome.
對不起，這對我也太突然了
Look, I'm sorry, okay? It wasn't like it was planned.
但就是發生了，拜託
Let me guess, it just happened. Please.
聽著，我知道你不喜歡他，但是…
Look, I know you don't like him, but...
其實我恨他
Actually, I hate the guy.
為什麼？
Why?
我以為你不至於愛上他
I thought you were better than that.
那這又說明什麼？
What's that supposed to mean?
我才是一直等你的人，不是他
I'm the one who's always been there for you, not him.
我早愛上你了
I'm in love with you.
不過顯然你沒有同感
And it's clear that you don't feel the same way.
- 這…  - 不
- It's... - Don't.
沒什麼好說了
There's nothing to say.
還有，克拉蕾
And, Clary,
他只是利用你獲得聖盃
he's just using you to get the Cup.
西蒙…
Simon...
你母親也能這麼做
Your mother was the only other person who could do that.
但我之前從沒這麼做過
But I've never been able to do this before.
說明封印住的不僅是你的回憶
Apparently the block wasn't just repressing your memories,
還有你的能力
but your abilities as well.
- 傑斯，我…  - 別跟我說
- Jace, I... - Don't tell me.
你急需一個裸模來畫畫
You have a drawing emergency and you need a nude model.
- 沒那個心情  - 聽著！
- I'm not in the mood. - Listen!
我知道我媽媽將聖盃藏哪兒了
I know where my mom hid the Cup.
克拉蕾…
Clary...
你看上去很不同
Wow, you look different.
嗯，這只是我借來的
Yeah, it's just something I borrowed.
我是說，你穿得很漂亮
I mean, nice outfit. It's good.
好吧，現在我沒空聊 抱歉
Yeah, I can't talk now. Sorry.
（西蒙，克拉蕾剛進她家）
- 克拉蕾  - 我來拿塔羅牌
- Clary. - I came for the tarot cards.
- 為什麼？  - 我需要他們
- Why?          - I need them.
你懂的，就是我媽媽畫的那些？
You know, the ones that Mom painted?
我就想快點看看
I just need to look at them really quickly,
然後就還你，我發誓
and I'll give them back, I promise.
武器別帶進來
Those can't come in here.
這是和平之地
This is a peaceful house.
放那兒
Put them in there.
今天感覺怎麼樣？
How are you feeling today?
很好，很好
Fine. Just fine.
小伙子，走調了
Young man, that piano is out of tune.
拜託別彈了
Please don't.
小伙子
Young man.
別彈！
Stop!
那首曲
That song.
不是我的最愛
Not one of my favorites.
停下來！
Stop!
拿來看看
Let's have a look.
快跑！
Get out!
你好，多蘿西夫人
Hey, Madame Dorothea.
有看見克拉蕾嗎？
Have you seen Clary?
我剛收到短信說她在這兒
I just got a text that said she was here.
沒有
No.
好吧，我只是…
Okay. Well, I'll just...
西蒙！
Simon!
西蒙，這不是真的她！
Simon, it's not really her!
西蒙！
Simon!
我來照顧他
I'll take care of him.
西蒙！
Simon!
她拿走了聖盃！
She's got the Cup!
西蒙！
Simon!
對不起
I'm sorry.
傑斯！
Jace!
圖符不起作用
The runes aren't working.
西蒙，跟著我
Simon, you follow me.
把他們切碎
You cut these up.
不要 夠了
Don't. You've done enough.
別這樣對她 這不是她的錯
Don't talk to her like that. This isn't her fault.
- 不，你說的對，是你的錯  - 伊莎貝爾！
- No, you're right. This is your fault. - Isabelle!
亞力克一直都告誡你你會受傷
Alec kept telling you that you were going to get hurt.
你會讓我們都受傷
You were going to get us all hurt.
現在他卻快死了
Now he's the one dying.
我們需要找到聖盃
Well, we needed to get the Mortal Cup.
但還有別的辦法
But there were other ways to do it
沒必要為此傷害你的摯友
than getting your best friend killed.
去找霍奇
Why don't you go get Hodge.
我從沒想讓亞力克這樣
I never wanted anything to happen to Alec.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我們同意一起做的，我們一個團隊
We agreed to do this together. We're a team.
有了克拉蕾，我們就不是一個團隊了
Since Clary got here, we haven't been a team.
霍奇
Hodge!
亞力克受傷了
Alec's getting worse.
我知道
I know.
我已經叫人來了
I've already sent for someone.
你得到聖盃了嗎？
Did you get the Cup?
然後呢？
What now?
霍奇？
Hodge?
你根本不知道
You have no idea what it's like
克拉夫的詛咒是什麼滋味
living with the Clave's curse,
不能從這兒踏出一步
unable to set so much as a foot outside,
連開窗戶都害怕
afraid to even open a window.
克拉蕾，別太怪我
Try not to judge me too harshly, Clary.
霍奇，你要做什麼？
Hodge, what have you done?
我知道你終將把聖盃給我
I always knew you would bring me the Cup.
只是時間問題而已
It was only a matter of time.
我媽媽在哪兒？
Where is she?
她很好
She's fine.
你得到了想要的，現在放她走
You got what you want. Now let her go.
我得看看這是不是真的
I have to make sure you gave me the real one.
每個人為了聖盃都會不擇手段
Everybody wants the Cup for the wrong reason.
那你沒有嗎？
And you don't?
擁有它
With this Cup,
我才能淨化我的血統
I can cleanse our bloodlines,
拯救我們的種族
Save our race.
你也許不太瞭解人類歷史
You might not know much about mundane history,
聽著，當人們談論保護種族時
but I can tell you when people start talking about preserving a race,
從沒好事發生
it never goes well.
這就是為何我媽媽要用一生時間隱瞞你
That's why my mom spent her whole life hiding it from you.
不
No.
她不是要藏聖盃
She wasn't hiding the Cup.
她是要藏著你
She was hiding you.
喝下去
Drink.
我不會喝的
I'm not gonna drink that.
你為什麼這麼害怕？
Why are you so afraid?
你還沒出生就已經喝過它了
You've been drinking this since before you were born.
我在你媽媽懷孕時就給她喝過
I fed it to your mother while you were in her womb.
快點，克拉蕾
Come on, Clary.
你現在應該猜到
You must have guessed by now.
你所有神奇的天賦
All these amazing talents
都是你母親一直想要壓制的
that your mother so desperately tried to suppress,
你覺得它從何而來？
where do you think they came from?
你是我女兒
You're my daughter.
我的血液流淌在你的身上
My blood runs in your veins.
現在…
Now...
喝
Drink.
快喝！
Drink!
把它拿出來！
Take that out!
不！
No!
有人進入穿梭門了
Someone just went through the Portal.
我去看看
I'll go check.
抱歉
Sorry.
我有點太激動了
I got a bit carried away.
盧克，你是…
Luke, you're a...
克拉蕾，聽我說，聽著 別害怕
Clary, listen to me, listen. Don't be afraid.
- 聽著，好嗎？  - 別碰我！
- Listen, right? - Don't touch me!
嘿，別這樣
Hey, there's no need for that.
那東西還會回來
That thing will be back.
這兒不安全
We are not safe out here.
我跳進穿梭門，為了躲瓦倫丁
I jumped through the Portal to get away from Valentine.
我以為會到我媽媽那兒
I thought I'd end up with my mom.
但是我卻到了最不想來的地方
Instead, I ended up in the last place I wanted to be.
聽著，穿梭門帶你來
Listen, the Portal brought you here
說明你一定想到我了
because you must have been thinking of me.
你內心深處仍信任我
Deep inside, you know you can trust me.
你說過一點都不在乎
You said you couldn't care
我們發生什麼事情
less what happened to either of us.
你跟別人一樣，只是想要聖盃
You just want the Cup, like everyone else.
我說過要保護你，我還能怎麼做？
I said that to protect you. What else could I do?
這次我得一直照看你
Been keeping an eye on you this whole time.
在旅店那兒的是你
That was you at the hotel.
話說投的好啊
Good throw, by the way.
我怎麼辦？
What about me?
你怎麼辦？
What about you?
我們說好的
We had a deal.
我仍然沒得到聖盃，不是嗎？
Well, I still don't have my Cup, do I?
我一直信守諾言
I held up my end of the bargain.
不，你沒有
No, you didn't.
我把聖盃給你了
I gave you the Cup.
是你給克拉蕾的 不是我的錯
You handed it to Clary. That's not my fault.
幫我解咒
Now lift it.
聽著，這都是你腦子想的
Listen, it's all in your head.
不，不！
No. No!
有詛咒
There's a spell.
真的？詛咒？
Really? A spell?
這只是問題的借口
That's just an excuse for a real problem
在這兒
in there.
你以為我真的可以解決嗎？
Do you really think I can fix that?
我給你聖盃了，你幫我帶走恐懼
I give you the Cup, you take away the fear.
沒有聖盃我也一樣寸步難行
Without the Cup, I'm as stuck as you are.
我的恐懼才是真的
Except my fear is real.
每個地下生物
Every Downworlder,
每個守護者
every member of the Clave,
每個暗影獵人都在穿梭門另一側
every Shadowhunter on both sides of the Portal
找我
is looking for me right now.
我才需要一切幫助
I'm going to need all the help I can get.
瓦倫丁，你不必這樣的
You don't have to go through with this, Valentine.
邪靈從來沒到過神院
A demon has never set foot in the Institute.
現在是時候讓他們來了
Well, maybe it's time they did.
我等這等好多年了
I've been waiting all these years to do this.
我別無選擇
Clary's given me no choice.
她會回來的
She'll come back.
真的嗎？
Really?
你敢確定？
And what makes you so sure?
這兒有她需要的人，像她需要她媽媽一樣
There's someone here she wants as much as her mother.
你可以騙他們
If you lie and tell them
說他們都是你的孩子
they're both your children,
你這樣就能讓他們心碎
you'll break their hearts.
那又怎麼樣？
What can I say?
心碎的人最聽話
The broken make the best followers.
看看你
Look at you.
愛就是滅亡
To love is to destroy.
霍奇到底在哪堙H
Where the hell is Hodge?
我們沒多少時間了
We don't have much time.
- 這弄對了嗎？  - 不
- Does this look right to you? - No.
快看
Hey, look.
馬格努斯？
Magnus?
我需要這些，要很多
I'm going to need all of this. Lots of it.
拿著
Take this.
封鎖此地
Lock this place down.
殺死一切異族
Those who are not allies must be killed.
別動 它們
Don't do that!
瓦倫丁
Valentine.
喬納森
Jonathan.
你怎麼知道我的真名？
How do you know my real name?
沒人這樣叫過我
Nobody calls me that.
是真的嗎？
Is it true?
瓦倫丁是我父親？
Is Valentine my father?
他曾是個好人
You know, he was a great man,
在和守護者衝突之前
until his conflict with the Clave.
但你媽媽偷走聖盃後
But when your mother ran away with the Cup,
他害怕遭守護者懲罰
he was just so afraid of retribution from the Clave,
他燒燬了住處
he burned their house down to the ground.
他要世人相信他死了
He wanted the world to believe he was dead.
我們在灰燼塈鋮鴗@個男人
In the ashes, we found the remains of a man
和小孩
and a child.
等等，一個小孩？
Wait a second, there was a child?
瓦倫丁怒火中燒
Valentine was so enraged, he wanted her to believe
他想要她相信他和他兒子都死了
he killed himself and their son,
你的哥哥
your brother.
我有個哥哥？
I have a brother?
喬納森·克奡策咱情P摩根斯坦
Jonathan Christopher Morgenstern.
你撒謊
You're lying.
我姓名是傑斯·維蘭德
My name is Jace Wayland.
我是維蘭德家族的
And my family are the Waylands.
你以為只有克拉蕾被封存了記憶嗎？
You think Clary is the only one with a block in her mind?
讓你看看什麼是真相
Let me show you the truth.
你沒有馴服它，你毀了它
You didn't tame him. You broke him.
不！你…
No! You...
你不是我父親
You are not my father.
我來是要讓你知道自己到底是誰
I came back to help you understand who you really are.
我懂你在這不開心
I know you're unhappy here.
要守很多規矩
Plagued by rules.
你的名字輩分僅次於我
Your place is next to me.
你是摩根斯坦家族一員
You're a Morgenstern.
你是我兒子
And you're my son.
我叫傑斯·維蘭德
My name is Jace Wayland.
我是維蘭德家族的
I'm a Wayland.
抱歉告訴你這個消息
Sorry to break this to you,
但也是時候該知道了
but it's time you heard the truth.
不
Don't.
只是理解方式的問題
It's all a matter of perception.
看到了嗎？摩根斯坦
You see, Morgenstern.
- 拿著  - 好
- Take this. - Okay.
好
Okay.
伊莎貝爾
Isabelle.
克拉蕾？
Clary?
我們找到你媽媽了
Yeah, we found your mom.
他們找到她了
They found her.
在神院
She's at the Institute.
阿拉塈J
Alaric.
我是盧克，你看到了嗎？
It's Luke. Can you see it?
是的，我看到了
Yeah, I see it.
兄弟們，得走了
Hey, guys, we have to go.
盧克需要咱們
Luke needs us.
我們去哪？
Where are we headed?
神院
The Institute.
我們這是在破壞協議
We'd be breaking the accords.
不變身就沒關係
Not if we stay human.
走，兄弟們！
Let's go, guys!
快走，快走！
Go, go, go, go!
快，動起來！
Come on, move it!
準備就緒！
Ready to go!
一切聽指揮
They've all been briefed.
他是阿拉塈J，我們的人
This is Alaric. He's one of us.
走吧
Go ahead.
如果需要可以將頭伸出窗外
You can hang your head out the window if you need to.
我是狼人
I'm a werewolf
不是金毛犬
not a golden retriever.
西蒙！
Simon!
在這等，我會回來
Just wait here, I'll be back.
啥？不 伊莎貝爾，我不能…
What? No. Isabelle, I can't just...
不，伊莎貝爾！
No. Isabelle!
回來，伊莎貝爾，你去哪？
Come on, Isabelle, where are you?
好，上！
All right, move it!
快點，上！
Come on, move it!
好吧
All right.
狼人來救我們了
The werewolves are here to save us.
難以置信我這麼說
Never thought I'd say that.
伊莎貝爾
Finally! Isabelle.
打開
Hey, open up the door.
起作用了
It looks like he's responding.
他能挺過來
He'll survive.
小心
And be careful.
有人入侵
You're being invaded.
召集所有邪靈…
Summoning all these bloody demons...
跑！
Run!
快跑！
- 走哪堙H  - 那有另一個出口！
- Where are we going? - There's another exit!
等等
Wait.
伊莎貝爾！
Isabelle!
- 我差點殺死你了  - 是啊
- I almost killed you. - Yeah.
你還好嗎？
You okay?
- 沒事，我沒事  - 來吧
- Yeah, yeah. I'm fine. - Come on.
這破地方全是邪靈
This place is full of demons.
這不可能
That's impossible.
神院是聖地
The Institute is hallowed ground.
他們還不知情
Yeah, no one seems to have told them that.
肯定有內鬼放他們進來
Someone on the inside must have let them in.
原是救援行動
This is a rescue mission.
我們可沒裝備作戰
We are not equipped to fight demons.
- 分開！  - 這邊！這邊！
- Spread out! - That way! That way!
後退！快！
Move back! Come on!
阿拉塈J，我們需要支援！
We could use some help here, Alaric!
阿拉塈J！
Alaric!
振作點，這肯定還有別的出入，是吧？
Come on, there must be some other way out of here, right?
不，這堥S有，西蒙！
No, there isn't, Simon!
我們撐不了多久！
We can't hold them much longer!
讓開
Step away.
讓開！
Step away!
克拉蕾，這是什麼圖符？
Clary, which rune is that?
我也不知道，它是…
I don't know, it's just...
- 我從沒見過  - 真的嗎？
- I've never seen it before. - Really?
不在書上
It's not in the book.
它在消退
It's fading.
肯定有地方放他們進來
Here, they're coming in through somewhere.
我得去阻止他們
I'm going to stop them.
快點
Come on.
你們現走
You guys go.
我們墊後
We'll catch up.
不！
No!
他們從屋頂下來的，跟上
They're coming from the dome. Come on.
喬絲琳
Jocelyn,
我一直惦記你
you never left my heart.
我現在帶你回家
I've come to take you home.
她哪兒也不去
She's not going anywhere.
你怎麼上來的
How did you get up here?
你比我想像的更強大
You're even more powerful than I anticipated.
離她遠點
Get away from her.
幹嘛？
What the hell?
聽他說
Just listen to what he has to say.
不是你想的那樣
It's not what you think.
終於…
Finally...
我的兩個孩子團聚了
Both my children together.
我女兒
My daughter
和我兒子
and my son.
對不起，克拉蕾
I'm so sorry, Clary.
我原先不知道
I didn't know.
瓦倫丁在撒謊
Valentine's lying.
你是邁克爾·維蘭德的兒子
You're Michael Wayland's son.
盧克說我哥哥已經死了
Luke said my brother is dead.
他死於火災
He died in a fire,
他們在灰燼塈鋮鴠L遺骸
and they found his remains in the ashes.
我帶喬納森一起逃跑的
I took Jonathan with me when I ran.
那孩子遺骨是狼人所為
The bones were of a child killed by wolves.
但願這不是真的
I wish it wasn't true.
她不願意相信
She doesn't want to believe you
因為她愛上你了，喬納森
because she is in love with you, Jonathan.
我以為你叫傑斯
I thought your name was Jace.
傑斯是小名
Jace is a nickname.
喬納森·克奡策咱情K
Jonathan Christopher...
J.C.
傑斯
Jace.
把手在這
There's the lever.
你進去，我阻止他們
You go close the dome and I'll hold them off.
把聖盃拿出來，克拉蕾
Take out the Cup, Clary.
拿出聖盃！
Take out my Cup!
我要你拿！
I want that Cup!
你說過不傷害她！
You said you wouldn't hurt her!
夠了！
Enough!
說夠了
That's enough.
現在！
Now!
卡住了！
It's stuck!
關掉它！
Close it!
不行！
I can't!
好像少了一塊！
I think there's a piece missing!
克拉蕾！
Clary!
我非常需要它
I really need this.
媽媽？
Mom?
- 去找其他人  - 好
- Find the others. - All right.
好吧，你是要上還是下呢？
All right, you want to take the upstairs or the down?
我對底下不感冒
I'm not too crazy about the basement.
我撐不了太久！
I can't hold them back any longer!
西蒙，快點！
Simon, hurry!
克拉蕾！
Clary!
嗨，盧克先生
Hello, Mr. Garroway.
看起來今天你很悲劇，嗯？
Looks like you're having a rough day, eh?
我覺得這種情況下直接殺了你
I guess the humane thing to do in this situation
會仁慈點
would be to put you down.
你想看我變身嗎？
But you wanted to see me change.
是的
I do.
起來！
Get up!
那麼，你到底要反抗到什麼時候？
So, boy, how far do you want to take this?
到死為止
To the end.
西蒙！
Simon!
伊莎貝爾！
Isabelle!
靠著我
Lean on me.
出去！快！
Get out! Go on!
離開這兒
Get out of here.
快跑！
Come on!
走！
Go!
聽說你喜歡彈琴
Somebody told me that you like to play music.
歌德會為此驕傲的
Johann would be very proud.
你該死在拉齊爾劍下
Now you shall die by Raziel's sword.
住手！
Stop!
要麼我就丟了它！
Or I'll drop it!
你不會那麼做的
You don't want to do that.
克拉蕾，別給他
Don't give it to him, Clary.
你先聽我說
I need you to listen to me.
我是你爸爸
As your father,
我求你了
I'm begging you.
要是我爸爸就一定懂我
If you'd been a real dad,
懂得聖盃在哪
you'd know me well enough to imagine where the Cup is,
知道我心底想的地方
where my deepest thoughts are taking it.
你一點都不懂我
You don't know the first thing about me.
你不是我爸…
You're not my dad...
永遠不是
And you never will be.
我保證你不會再見到我
I promise, you'll never have to see me again.
克拉蕾，謝謝
Thank you, Clary.
沒有聖盃，我們會輸的
Without this Cup, we are lost.
不是「我們」
Not "we."
是你
You.
克拉蕾！
Clary!
- 不！抓住我！  - 決不！
- No! Don't let go! - Never!
這兒！
Here!
你還好嗎？
Are you okay?
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道你之前為什麼那樣做了
I understand why you did what you did.
我原諒你
And I forgive you.
我要你知道
I want you to know,
我會為你保密
your secret's safe with me.
她怎麼樣了？
So, how's she doing?
情況穩定了
Stable.
醫生不知道她喝過什麼
The doctors don't know what she took,
只能等
so we just have to wait.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我覺得我只是一個老古董
I guess I'm an old romantic.
我總希望當我向某人說
I always hoped that when I finally said
「我愛你」時，她會說同樣的話
"I love you" to someone, she'd say the same thing back.
那個人會的
And that someone will.
但願吧
Yeah, I know.
你很累了
Hey, you're tired.
去休息吧，我們會照看好她
Go sleep, we'll take care of her.
好，抱一個
Yeah, come on.
我喜歡你收拾這
I like what you've done with the place.
我只是耍了些把戲
I've got a few tricks up my sleeve.
克拉蕾，我們真怕你不會回來了
Clary, we're afraid you're not coming back.
只是現在跟你作伴真的很難
It's just really hard to be around you right now.
對我來說也一樣
It's hard for me as well.
但是這不僅僅是我們
But this is about more than us.
你有不可思議的天賦，我們需要你
You have an incredible gift, and we need you.
我需要你
I need you.
我不知道
I just don't know.
還記得我說過從沒見過天使？
Remember when I said I'd never seen an angel?
我撒謊了
Well, I lied.
你是我見過最勇敢的凡人
You're still the bravest mundane I've ever met.
我可不是凡人
I'm not a mundane.
等等，傑斯！
Wait, Jace!
慢慢來啊
You took your time.
你說過你需要我
You said you needed me.
你該好好保存它
You should keep that safe.
我會的
Yeah.
我可以抱著你嗎…
Is it okay if I...
我能…
Do I...
- 這樣可以嗎…  - 沒關係
- Is it okay if I... - Yeah.
聽著，克拉蕾，我不相信它
Look, Clary, I don't believe it.
這似乎不是真的，不在我的心
It doesn't feel like the truth, not in my heart.
我只是不懂如何去面對這個世界
I just don't know how to look at the world anymore.
我看不到街道，紅綠燈和車
I don't see streets and traffic lights and cars.
眼前只是邪靈和天使
I see demons and angels.
一切都變了
Everything's different.
世界還是一樣的
The world's the same.
你才是變了的那個
You're the one who's different.
你還記得霍奇說的嗎？
Don't you remember what Hodge said?
什麼？
What?
所以故事都是真的
All the stories are true.
感謝觀影